You realize okay, I need to stop working this desk job. I hate yeah, I don't want to go back to college
I want to become a machine learning engineer for Amazon for Twitch in particular. Yeah
What would you do start over right now?
Okay, so look I
Actually really like that question because it always makes me think of like all the stuff that I did right all the things I did wrong
One thing I do like about that question is like you know
I like how you ask like Twitch and Amazon because a lot of people I think set them so it was all for potential failure
When they don't know what company exactly they want to go for because there is a clear distinction between those like big
FANG tech companies so you know for those big FANG tech companies if I was pressed on time
The only thing I would do is lead code and
That's an answer that a lot of people don't like but all I would do as the juniors going into snow experience
It just lead code till my eyes and fingers don't work. Can you go deep into that? Do you mean lead code data structures?
Right right design you name it algorithms
reversal link tree you mean that yep and not in particular how to build an actual model yep
I would a hundred percent go fully into lead code to gain that junior position in those big Fang tech companies
the expectation for juniors is
Very close to zero very close is like there's no expectations out
There is no and like I work there. I've interviewed a bunch of juniors. I've gone through the like the nuance
I've done I've done it all you know
I've seen it but on both sides of it been a junior at a big tech company
I know how it works and you know the reason why there's no expectations is
To set yourself up for success while also protecting the business side expectations, but
Yeah, I would just grind lead code. I would just grind grind grind lead code while you know on the side reading and understanding things about machine learning
I would lead code first machine learning seconds. Yes like this like would you say
Everyone mean hopefully you I mean you should work full-time job. Hopefully if you could fortunately
After you 9 to 5 if not during you 9 to 5 but after you from
6 to 9 lead code then Saturday Sunday machine learning. I would even put like maybe like I would do
6 to 10 lead code and Saturday like when you wake up. Let's say you wake up brush your teeth. I would say 10 to 3 p.m
Lead code and then Sunday you're late reading 2 to 4 to the 5 machine learning. It's like
If you can get into a Fang company as a junior for an ML team they will teach you everything you need to know
Wow, yeah, they'll build you from the ground up and that is like truly how it works
Like if you the best case scenario best case is if you're already somehow in school for some like ML programmer
Emblems or tips or something like that and you have the academic courses on your resume or you have the academic knowledge
To talk about a conversation, but when it comes to literally the technical
Challenges or technical you know requirements only lead code
What programming language though?
Python Python Python yeah, not 100% 100% not JavaScript
No, no, no, no, no, if you want to be an ML
In the ML space first of all, I think leaco is like the best language to lead code
I that's just my opinion. I think it's just like super easy and it's like you know very you know easy to understand
But once you get in through your lead code skills and through through your lead code grind all of the ML stuff is basically written in Python
A lot of go for like the microservices the lamb does deployments and all that stuff
However, I just want to double down one thing if you're not going for the big Fang company, right?
Let's say you don't want to go work for the twitch or the amazon to google and you want to work for like you know
Maybe a startup or a different company whatever then my answer completely changes then it's
Grind machine learning and become a subject matter expert like become that bad ass in the field like depth
Just know everything know everything model every way to you know
Clean the data everything become that master so when you join a company you can
Just floor them with how much you know how about this the four four five main things, right?
If you had to really point out if you're trying to go for startup
Come come first um, you know fang for startup. Yeah, we need to get what you need to learn
Yeah for a startup world. I would definitely say the most important things are one you have to
Be practical you're that's the most thing it's to be practical
So you can as much as like the thing I always warn people who like get into ML is don't go too hard into academia
Like academia is very important and like you have to have you have to know it
But I think be practical you know how can you actually use it? Can you actually program something?
Do you know how to you know use tools that career databases?
So to be very you know, let's let's actually give you that list one
Can you career databases?
Can you pull data from databases and what is what even if for that sequel?
So do you know sequel are you good with sequel right that's number one number two?
Can you build a pipeline that does a few processes with sequel?
So I say you grab a bunch of data and you have to do operation one operation two operation three
Can you do that doubt the second piece of advice I'll give someone
Three, can you benchmark your model?
How do we know your model is good and how do we know if I just you know put a bunch of if else statements
It's better than that as dumb as that sounds you'd be surprised at how many people skip that third step or
Don't understand how important that step is for business. They want to know cool your machine learning engine
That sounds awesome. You've set a bunch of key words and you've you've already impressed with your knowledge
How do we know your model is better than me putting a bunch of stuff myself a heuristic rule, right?
So make sure you can sell your model and and do it with with the proper metrics
For deploy your model. This is one that I know a lot of people never do
It's actually deploy it into production for example, Chris. Let's say you and I are building a website, right?
I build mine all on local host. That's exactly exact same thing. We're both using JavaScript
Let's say we both use React. I make my Chris my website so good. You're gonna be so jealous
And you're like, oh, yeah, let me see it. I'm like, uh, okay. How can you how do you want me to send you the files?
Docker like
Docker. Yeah, but you'd be like, what why can't you just deploy it? And if I say I don't know how to deploy it
You'd be like, oh man. That's uh, that's a bit of an eyebrow razor, right? So the deployment part is is also just
Extremely make it accessible
Make it accessible in showcase that you know the end-to-end process
Why is that so important though?
Because it showcases that not only do you know how to train them all locally
It shows you how you can actually use it in production use it in a system that's not your local computer
Because it's easy if I have a mall in my local computer
I could run a script that just says you know make it inference. It works in my machine
It works on my machine. It works on my machine. Why would it not work?
But then the question is and it's so different than like a website
You have to understand how to deploy a model into a service that can be used by other systems other services in your ecosystem